# **Mehrdad Nateghian**

Mobile: + (44) 785 250 4801 - Email: mehrdud@gmail.com

I am a solutions architect with experience in different industry sectors such as payment systems, online gaming, insurance and market research. I have over 15 years of experience in designing and implementing high volume transactional applications and enterprise solutions.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Lead Solution Architect**

Worldpay, October 2016 – Present

- Leads a team of solution architects focused on designing features and technical governance of Worldpay's Alternative Payments Platform
- Participates in Worldpay Service Oriented Architecture working group(SOP), defining standards and evaluating technology suites for SOP
- Ensures platform's compliance with UK and EU regulatory body's regulations
- Explores new business opportunities and features alongside product manager and business partners (PSD2, new APMs, etc...)
- Works with development teams to implement CI/CD pipeline automation projects
- Designed RESTful API reference implementation
- Technology evaluation (Akka & Akka.Net, Apache Kafka, Ansible Tower, etc...)
- Design centralised foreign exchange service for all Worldpay platforms (service oriented architecture, contact first design approach, RESTful APIs, distributed calculation mechanisms, working on caching mechanism)

## **Solution Architect**

IGT, November 2014 - October 2016

- Supported project delivery lifecycle from RFP through development, delivery and support
  phases by engaging and managing the relationships with product teams, customisation
  teams, 3rd party providers and global clients
- Performed gap analysis on existing products, product roadmaps and customer needs and provides solution proposal translating business requirements to technical requirements, producing high level architecture diagrams, detailing selected products and any necessary customisation required by the client, integration with other systems in client platform
- Designed a solution for new UK regulatory requirements for IGT gaming platform. The solution is deployed for major UK based retail clients.
- Solution architect for projects to upgrade clients platform from legacy to new IGT platform

#### **Technical Specialist**

Client Facing Technology (CFT), Willis Towers Watson, July 2013 - November 2014

- Produced and maintained portfolio of over 80 different client facing systems in the business and categorised IT offerings in CFT domain based on line of business, geographical distribution, and strategic value of the tool using TOGAF concepts
- Technical lead on architecture in scope of client facing technology with focus on business, application and data architecture using TOGAF

• Designed and implemented a self-service reporting proof of concept for broking platforms

#### **Technical Architect**

TNS Global, Jun 2010 - Jul 2013

- Supported TNS Global IS for implementing Kantar IS strategy
- Gathered and analysed requirements, produced technical specification, and ensured application architecture and implementation meets the standards of the group.
- Planned and managed upgrade project for new TNS client delivery platform
- Designed and developed user management system incorporating business logic, Active
   Directory management and SSO solution for client delivery platform
- Managed offshore development team of developers, testers, and project managers to deliver a range of SharePoint and custom ASP.Net based solutions to the business including media streaming solution, SSO solution, and archiving tools
- Designed and developed new functionalities for QlikView Business Intelligence

## **Senior Software Engineer**

SimplicityIT, Apr 2008 - Jun 2010

Lead developer on multiple web applications, web services, E-Commerce solutions

## **Software Engineer**

Jannuzzi Smith, Jan 2007 - Apr 2008

Designed and developed "Content Management System" for "Royal College of Arts"

#### **Software Engineer**

Magfa ITDC (Tehran, Iran), Sep 2004 - Sep 2006

Architect and lead developer for "ViraCT Learning Content Management System"

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **MSc. Software Engineering**

London Metropolitan University, Sep 2008- Sep 2009

Thesis: "Distributed Intrusion Prevention System", protecting against DDoS attacks

### **BSc. Software Engineering**

Iran University of Science and Technology, Sep 2000- Sep 2004

• Thesis: "Word prediction for Persian on mobile phones supporting Symbian OS".

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## **Software Development Methodologies and Architecture**

 Agile, Scurm, Scaled Agile Framework (SAFe), Domain Driven Design, SOLID principles, Service Oriented Architecture(SOA), Microservices, Rational Unified Process(RUP), Extreme Programming (XP), Waterfall, TOGAF

## **Programming Languages and Technologies**

• Microsoft .Net and .Net Core, C#, RESTful services, Akka.Net, Python , XML, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, AngularJS, SQL Server, Ansible, Docker, Swagger, YAML, ASP.Net MVC

## **Knowledge of**

• UML, Java, Rational Unified Process(RUP), Azure, RabbitMQ, Apache Kafka, NHibernate, Identity Federation, VMWare, Apache and Linux, Cloud-based technologies(AWS, Azure)